RELAND BOYLE

Software Engineer

631-806-0019 reland.boyle@gmail.com • New York, NY • linkedin.com/in/relandboyle github.com/relandboyle

SUMMARY

Versatile software engineer and generalist with 15+ years of professional experience in product development, mechanical design, project management, vendor relations, compliance, and customer success. Known for rapidly becoming a subject matter expert and a source for reliable information. Highly attuned to the needs of the customer, the company, the team, and the product.

SKILLS

Strong: JavaScript (ES6+) - React - Redux - Express.js - Node.js - Docker - Kubernetes - OAuth 2.0 - SQL/NoSQL Database • Material UI • webpack • CSS/Sass/Less • Jest • Enzyme • Prometheus • Electron • AWS • Linux • HTML Experienced: TypeScript - Python - Auth0 - Git/GitHub - Travis CI - Grafana - Google Cloud - Linode - Wordpress

Work Experience

DataCaliper - NetSuite Developer

November 2021 - February 2022

- Developed SuiteScript 2.0 programs within SuiteCloud Developer Framework to customize NetSuite instances for 5 clients
- Produced Advanced PDF Templates, Workflows, and Formula Fields to reduce wait time and cognitive load by up to 60%
- Typically responded to client requests within 24 hours with effective, creative solutions and implemented within 5 business days

KR8S for Kubernetes - Software Engineer

September 2021 - December 2021

- Created a React/Electron single-page desktop application under the OS Labs tech accelerator to visualize and monitor Kubernetes cluster health and performance metrics, providing developers with real-time insight into the impact of changes made to the deployed application, streamlining development and reducing the need to review and respond to logs by up to 75%
- Automated deployment of a Dockerized multi-service React-based e-commerce application in a local Kubernetes cluster with preconfigured Prometheus server and over 10 Grafana dashboards for a 50% reduction in setup time for new Kubernetes users
- Leveraged Material UI, React Router, to rapidly construct accessible, production-quality navigation components, reducing the load on the KR8S development team and ensuring a highly consistent, high-quality user experience with minimal overhead

CS Study Buddy - Software Engineer

September 2021 - October 2021

- Designed a single-page React application with 5+ views using React Router to allow developers to share, search, and filter real interview prompts as well as to connect for pair programming and practice sessions in a realistic simulated interview environment
- Managed state in a React front-end using functional components and React Hooks, doubling development velocity
- Integrated OAuth 2.0 for credible, secure signup and login via four mainstream strategies (Google, GitHub, Facebook, Slack)
- Implemented Express framework over Node.js and followed the middleware design pattern to handle routing and authentication
- Stored and served 100's of user-generated prompts in a PostgreSQL object-relational database well-positioned for future scaling

NowNotes - Software Engineer

August 2021 - September 2021

 Constructed a full-stack CRUD application for note taking using JavaScript DOM manipulation without a frontend framework, employing Express.js to facilitate connection to a MongoDB non-relational database while minimizing the size of the code base

Rich Brilliant Willing - Assistant Director of Operations

January 2016 - August 2021

- Optimized processes across departments, automating repetitive tasks and implementing integrations between Oracle NetSuite ERP/CRM and 4 secondary platforms, working with tech such as NetSuite Workflows and SuiteScript Developer Framework
- Achieved 100% product compliance with relevant consumer product safety standards and internal performance standards
- Founded and managed RBW's Customer Success Team, hired CSR's, established metrics and service level agreements, reduced post-sale support cases from 15% to 5% of all sales while mentoring team members and generating internal tech wiki
- Routinely handled \$1M+ custom projects from ideation through design validation, manufacturing, delivery, and post-sale support

EDUCATION

Codesmith - Full-stack JavaScript - Residency for Experienced Engineers - Certificate

November 2021

Dassault Systemes - Certified SolidWorks Professional - Certificate

June 2020

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Tech Talks Sponsored by Single Sprout: User Experience Best Practices
- RBW Help Center (https://support.rbw.com/kb/en)
- CS Study Buddy Group Host / Instructor

October 2021 August 2021

June 2021